Preliminary Inventory of the Robert B. Dresser Papers, 1941-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert B. Dresser Papers,
1941-1967
67017
Dresser, Robert B.
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, public addresses, leaflets, and writings, relating to American relations with Vietnam, Cuba, and Panama, the Korean War, communism, tax laws, civil rights, armaments, and the United Nations.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United Nations.; Communism.; Communism--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Arms control.; Korean War, 1950-1953.; Taxation--United States.; Cuba.; Panama.; Vietnam.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
List of Certain Articles Published as Advertisements
- #1 - Communism and The House Un-American Activities Committee - Feb. 12, 1961 (Box 1)
- #2 - Communism and The House Un-American Activities Committee - Second article March 1, 1961
- #3 - Communism and The House Un-American Activities Committee - We Are Losing The Cold War - Third article Feb. 26, 1961
- #4 - Communism and The House Un-American Activities Committee - The Influence of Communism on Government Policy - Fourth article March 5, 1961
- #5 - Individual Liberty - The House Un-American Activities Committee and So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation - March 14, 1961
- #7 - "Operation Abolition" - Answer of Associated Industries of Rhode Island to Attack by Providence Journal and American Civil Liberties Union on San Francisco Riot Film - March 21, 1961
- #8 - The John Birch Society - Letter to the Editor of the Providence Journal - from Robert B. Dresser and Norman D. MacLeod - April 13, 1961
- #9 - The Real Issue in So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation - April 17, 1961
- #10 - The Cuban Crisis - April 24, 1961
- #11 - The Tragic Consequences of Our Policy Regarding Cuba - July 13, 1961
- #12 - The Tragic Consequences of Our Policy Regarding Cuba - Second article July 10, 1961
- #13 - The Tragic Consequences of Our Policy Regarding Cuba - Third article July 15, 1961
- #14 - The Truth About Trujillo and The Dominican Republic - July 18, 1961
- #15 - The Menace of Communism and What the Individual Can Do About It - July 20, 1961
- #16 - Foreign Aid - A Serious Menace to the U.S.A. - Aug. 11, 1961
- #17 - Disarmament - A Grave Menace to the U.S.A. - Aug. 18, 1961
- #18 - World Government - A Serious Threat to the U.S.A. - Aug. 22, 1961
- #19 - The United Nations - A Help Or A Hindrance? - Aug. 24, 1961
- #20 - Communism and Foreign Aid - Aug. 26, 1961
- #21 - Disarmament - Nuclear Testing - and the Cold War - Sept. 4, 1961
- #22 - Mutual Security, Foreign Aid and The Berlin Crisis - Sept. 9, 1961
- #23 - The Berlin Crisis - Sept. 12, 1961
- #26 - Letter to the Editor of The Providence Journal Re Gordon Hall and United States Day - Oct. 27, 1961
- #27 - The Alarming Inadequacy of Our Future Defense Plans - By Bonner Fellers, Brig.-Gen., U.S.A. (Ret'd.) - Oct. 30, 1961
- #28 - The United Nations - An Increasing Menace to the U.S.A. - Nov. 8, 1961
- #29 - The United Nations - An Increasing Menace to the U.S.A. - Second Article - Betrayal in the Congo - Senator Dodd's Speeches - Nov. 14, 1961
- #30 - The United Nations - An Increasing Menace to the U.S.A. - Third Article - Betrayal in the Congo (Continued) - Congressman Bruce's Speech - Nov. 17, 1961
- #31 - The Strange Performance of our State Department - Nov. 27, 1961
- #32 - The Communist Menace - Testimony of Eugene Lyons, Senior Editor of Reader's Digest - Nov. 30, 1961
- #33 - United Nations and State Department - The Outrageous Attack on Katanga - Dec. 14, 1961
- #35 - United Nations and State Department - The Outrageous Attack on Katanga - Second Article - Dec. 19, 1961
- #36 - The United States Should Withdraw From the United Nations and Compel Its Removal From This Country - Jan. 5, 1962
- Certain Articles on So-Called "Fair Housing" Legislation
  - #37 - The Case Against The Fair Housing Bill - Jan. 26, 1959
  - #38 - So-called Fair Housing Legislation - The Rhode Island Story - Aug. 1, 1959
  - #39 - The Case Against So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation - The Rhode Island Story of 1960 - Sept. 15, 1960
  - #40 - The Case Against So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation - Jan. 3, 1962
Supplemental List of Certain Articles Published as Advertisements
- #41 - Dangers Confronting the Nation - Statement for American Coalition - Feb. 1, 1962 (Box Box 1)
- #42 - Letter to Congressman Dole - March 14, 1962
- #43 - The Paramount Issue Before the American People Today Is That of Survival - March 15, 1962
- #44 - President Kennedy's Foreign Trade Bill - March 27, 1962
- #45 - Our Disastrous Foreign Policy - April 23, 1962
- #46 - Our Disastrous Domestic Policies - April 24, 1962
- #47 - A Program for Americans Who Desire to Retain Freedom - May 19, 1962
- #48 - The Importance of the Coming Election of Candidates for Congress - Sept. 5, 1962
- #49 - Voting Records of R.I. Senators and Congressmen - Oct. 22, 1962
- #50 - The Cuban Crisis of October 1962 - Oct. 31, 1962
- #51 - The United Nations' Outrageous Attack on Katanga - Jan. 9, 1963
- #52 - The Case Against So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation - Jan. 28, 1963
- #53 - The Administration's Shocking Proposal for World Government & Disarmament Should be Abandoned - Article No. 1 - May 8, 1963
- #54 - The Administration's Shocking Proposal for World Government & Disarmament Should be Abandoned - Article No. 2 - May 14, 1963
- #55 - The Administration's Shocking Proposal for World Government & Disarmament Should be Abandoned - Article No. 3 - May 15, 1963
- #56 - The Fair Housing Agitation - June 5, 1963
- #57 - The "Fair Housing" Riot - June 17, 1963
- #58 - The Limited Nuclear Test Ban Treaty Should Not be Ratified - Aug. 5, 1963
- #59 - The United States Is Disarming While Russia Is Arming - Aug. 7, 1963
- #60 - The Limited Nuclear Test Ban Treaty Should Not Be Ratified - Third Article Meaning of "Peaceful Co-Existence" - Aug. 16, 1963
- #61 - The Limited Nuclear Test Ban Treaty Should Not Be Ratified - Fourth Article Statements of Congressman Utt and Senator Thurmond - Aug. 19, 1963
- #62 - The Nuclear Test Ban Treaty - Fifth Article Do Unilateral Disarmers Influence Defense Policy? - Article by Allan H. Ryskind in Human Events for Aug. 10, 1963 - Aug. 20, 1963
- #63 - The Limited Nuclear Test Ban Treaty Should Not Be Ratified - Sixth Article Broadcast of Rear Admiral Ward - Aug. 21, 1963
- #64 - Are We Nearing the End of Our Republic? - Aug. 27, 1963
- #65 - The Limited Nuclear Test Ban Treaty Should Not Be Ratified - Seventh Article - Sept. 19, 1963
- #66 - The Renewed Demand For So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation Must Be Defeated. - Jan. 24, 1964
- #67 - The Pending Federal Civil Rights Bill Should Not Be Passed. - Feb. 5, 1964
- #68 - The Question of Enacting So-called "Fair Housing" Legislation Should be Submitted to the People at the November Election - Mar. 18, 1964
- #69 - The Panama Canal Issue - Apr. 13, 1964
- #70 - The Defeat of the "Fair Housing" Bill - A Reply to the Critics - Apr. 16, 1964
- #71 - The Steadily Increasing Menace of Communism - Apr. 17, 1964
- #72 - "Fair Housing", Civil Rights and Communism - June 17, 1964
- #73 - The Federal Civil Rights Bill - June 24, 1964
- #74 - Disarmament -- The Most Important Issue Facing The Country Today - June 29, 1964
- #75 - The Importance of Electing Senator Goldwater to the Presidency - Aug. 19, 1964
- #76 - Civil Rights or Civil Wrongs? - State Forced Housing Laws - Oct. 8, 1964
- #77 - Civil Rights or Civil Wrongs? - Federal Civil Rights Act - Oct. 9, 1964
- #78 - The Smear Campaign Against Senator Goldwater - Oct. 10, 1964
- #79 - Senator Thurmond (Democrat), of South Carolina Supports Senator Goldwater - Senator Thurmond's Historic Address Announcing His Decision - Oct. 13, 1964
- #80 - An Answer to The Attack Upon the John Birch Society and Other So-called Reactionary Groups - Oct. 14, 1964
- #81 - A Second Answer to The Attack by Dr. Larson's Group Upon So-called Reactionary Groups - Oct. 15, 1964
- #82 - The Charge That Senator Goldwater Is A "Warmonger" and "Trigger Happy" is Both False and Ridiculous - Oct. 16, 1964
- #83 - The Administration's Shocking Proposal For World Government and Disarmament - Oct. 21, 1964
- #84 - The Paramount Issue In The Present Campaign Is -- Shall The Administration's Policy of Disarming Be Continued? - Oct. 22, 1964
- #85 - An Answer To The Attack On The Conservative Organizations And Their Members - Letter to the Providence Journal - Oct. 24, 1964
- #86 - Question for All Voters - The Communist Parties, Both Here and Abroad, etc. - Oct. 29, 1964 and Oct. 30, 1964
- #87 - Comments on the National Election - Letter to The Providence Journal - Nov. 13, 1964
- #88 - The Pending "Forced" Housing Legislation - Feb. 27, 1965
- #89 - "Forced Housing Controversy" - April 28, 1965
- #90 - "Forced Housing, Civil Rights and Communism" - April 29 & 30, 1965
- #91 - The War in Vietnam - The Result of Earlier Blunders Occasioned by Incompetancy or Treachery A War, However, That Must Now be Fought and Won First Article - The Abandonment of China to the Communists - August 9, 1965
- #92 - The War in Vietnam (same as above) Second Article - Our Failure to Win the Korean War - August 10, 1965
- #93 - The War in Vietnam (same as above) Third Article - So We Intend to Win This War Or Is It To Be Another Korean War? - August 12, 1965
- #94 - The War in Vietnam (same as above) Fourth Article - How To Win The War - August 16, 1965
- #95 - The War in Vietnam (same as above) Fifth Article - The Tragic Performance of Our State Department - August 18, 1965
- #96 - The Panama Treaty - A Brazen and Dangerous Proposal by our Administration to Surrender Control of the Panama Canal, A Vital Link Between our Atlantic and Pacific Coasts - Sept. 30, 1965
- #97 - The Panama Treaty (same as above) 2nd Article Statement by Congressman Daniel J. Flood - Oct. 20, 1965
- #98 - The Dominican Republic Story - Another Shameful Surrender to the Communists - Nov. 4, 1965
- #99 - Communism - The Major Menace of our Time - Nov. 5, 1965
- #100 - An Answer to the Attack on the John Birch Society - Nov. 10, 1965
- #101 - The Amasing Influence of the Communists in the U.S.A. - The Voting Rights Act of 1965 "Drafted in Outline by the Communists Nine Years Before Its Passage Is An Outstanding Example. - Nov. 15, 1965
- #102 - U.S. Is Highly Vulnerable to Sabotage and Nuclear Attack - Nov. 16, 1965
- #103 - Communist Infiltration in Our Government and Elsewhere. - Nov. 17, 1965
- #104 - The United States Faces the Gravest Crisis In Its History--Its Very Survival Is At Stake - Jan. 25, 1966
- #105 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 1 - Jan. 26, 1966
- #106 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 2 - Jan. 27, 1966
- #107 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 3 - Jan. 28, 1966
- #108 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 4 - Jan. 29, 1966
- #109 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 5 - Jan. 31, 1966
  (Senator Russell's Statement in Manchester paper)
- #110 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 6 - Feb. 1, 1966
- #111 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 7 - Feb. 2, 1966
- #112 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 8 - Feb. 3, 1966
- #113 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 9 - Feb. 4, 1966
- #114 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 10 - Feb. 7, 1966
- #115 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 11 - Feb. 8, 1966
- #116 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 12 - Feb. 9, 1966
- #117 - The War In Vietnam And Our Foreign Policy No. 13 - Feb. 10, 1966
- #118 - The Disarming of the U.S.A. - Schlafly Statement re McNamara's Testimony Feb. 18, 1966
- #119 - The Disarming of the U.S.A. - Ryskind article republished Feb. 21, 1966
- #120 - The War In Vietnam Can Be Won Quickly - Article by Bonner Pellers March 29, 1966
- #121 - The Communist Menace - Will the American People Wake up to a Realization of it in Time to Save the Nation? - First Article - Our Government is Doing What the Communists Want Us To Do. August 10, 1966
- #122 - The Communist Menace - Will the American People Wake up to a Realization of it in Time to Save the Nation? - Second Article - Why is our Government Doing What the Communists Want Us To Do? August 11, 1966
- #123 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - my article of Jan. 27, 1967 in Prov. Journal - Jan. 31, 1967
- #124 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Second Article - Report of Cong. Utt to his Constituents on Trade with the Reds - published in Prov. Journal - March 13, 1967
- #125 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Third Article - Statement by Sen. Harry F. Byrd, Jr. (D.Va.) on Vietnam and Rhodesia - published in Prov. Journal - March 15, 1967
- #126 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Fourth Article - The Consular and Certain Other Treaties - published in Prov. Journal - March 29, 1967
- #127 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Fifth Article - Our Real Enemy - published in Prov. Journal - March 31, 1967
- #127(a) - Re Fair Housing - Ltr. to General Assembly Published in Prov. Journal Wed. April 5, 1967 - April 5, 1967
- #128 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Sixth Article - The U.S.A. Is In Great Peril - Published in Providence Journal April 6th - April 6, 1967
- #129 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Seventh Article - Obstacles to Survival - Published Providence Journal - April 7, 1967
- #130 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Eighth Article - Leeb Editorial, Published Providence Journal - April 12, 1967
- #131 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Ninth Article - The Attack on Rhodesia, Published Provideneo Journal - April 14, 1967
- #132 - An open letter opposing the Outer Space Treaty, mailed to all Senators April 25, 1967, not published in Providence Journal - April 25, 1967
- #133 - The Suicide of the U.S.A. - Tenth Article - "Peaceniks Are Nutniks" -- Loeb editorial, published in Providence Journal. No reprints made. - May 16, 1967
- #134 - Letter of July 26, 1967 to U.S. Senators, opposing 3 Panama Treaties, published in Providence Journal. - July 29, 1967
- #135 - Russia is Winning the Arms Race, Published in Providence Journal - Aug. 1, 1967
- #136 - Communism is the Major Menace of our Time, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 6, 1967
- #137 - Russia is Winning the Arms Race - Second Article - Why She is Winning, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 7, 1967
- #138 - Russia is Winning the Arms Race - Third Article - Our Plan to Disarm (excerpts from Article by Allan H. Ryskind, in HUMAN EVENTS for August 10, 1963), Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 8, 1967
- #139 - Russia is Winning the Arms Race - Fourth Article - Steps Taken to Disarm the U.S.A., Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 11, 1967
- #140 - Russia is Winning the Arms Race - Fifth Article - Steps Taken to Disarm the U.S.A., Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 12, 1967
- #141 - The War in Vietnam - First Article - Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 13, 1967
- #142 - The War in Vietnam - Second Article - "Why are We Pulling Our Best Punches in Vietnam?" - Speech of Representative Ford, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 14, 1967
- #143 - The War in Vietnam - Third Article - The Result of Earlier Blunders Occasioned by Incompetency or Treachery; However a War that Must Now Be Fought and Won - or Failure to Win the Korean War - Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 15, 1967
- #144 - The War in Vietnam Can Be Won Quickly - Article by General Bonner Fellers - Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 18, 1967
- #145 - The Communist Are Active in Stirring Up Internal Strife in the U.S.A. - Published in the Providence Journal - Sept. 19, 1967
- #146 - Civilian Review Boards, a Communist Conception - Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 20, 1967
- #147 - Conditions in the United States under Communism - First Article (excerpts from J. Edgar Hoovers "Masters of Deceit"), Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 21, 1967
- #148 - Conditions in the United States under Communism - Second Article - Herbert A. Philbrick's/first article on "Fifty Years of Soviet Hell", Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 22, 1967
- #149 - Conditions in the United States under Communism - Third Article - Herbert A. Philbrick's second article on "Fifty Years of Soviet Hell", Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 25, 1967
- #150 - Conditionsin the United States under Communism - Fourth Article - Herbert A. Philbrick's third article on "Fifty Years of Soviet Hell", Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 26, 1967
- #151 - Foreign Aid - An Enormous Waste of the Taxpayers' Money, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 27, 1967
- #152 - What a Mess We Are In - What To Do About It - First Article, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 28, 1967
- #153 - What a Mess We Are In - What To Do About It - Second Article, Published in Providence Journal - Sept. 29, 1967